Guide to the Norman Croom-Johnson Diaries
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Norman Croom-Johnson diaries
1886-1962
GEN MSS 886
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
34.41
(89 boxes)
The Norman Croom-Johnson Diaries consist of 217 autograph manuscript volumes, including 211 diaries with daily entries, 1905 January 1-1962 August 7; three volumes containing lists of theater, concerts, and other events attended by Croom-Johnson, 1901-1960; and three volumes containing a daily log of his residences and travels, 1886-1962. Early volumes are copies made by Croom-Johnson from his original diaries, with additional notes made at the time of copying. Entries concern Croom-Johnson's personal and professional life, travel, political events, the Savile Club, and interests in literature, theater and music. Each volume ends with a list of events attended by Croom-Johnson, noting dates, venues, and performers. Affixed to pages are materials relating to the diary entries, including newspaper clippings concerning legal cases, political events, and sports events; newspaper clippings of theater and music reviews; theater and concert programs; illustrated postcards from his travels; letters to Croom-Johnson; and photographs of him, his family, and friends.
Croom-Johnson, Norman
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Formerly owned by Clarissa Bell, 1962-1963, and the Savile Club, 1963-2003. Purchased from Maggs Brothers on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Norman Croom-Johnson (1886-1962)
Norman Croom-Johnson, British solicitor. Croom-Johnson practiced law in London and was a member of the Savile Club, 1920-1962. He began his diary in Wrexham, Wales, on 1905 January 1, and continued writing daily entries until several weeks before his death in London on 1962 September 13.
Scope and Contents
The Norman Croom-Johnson Diaries consist of 217 autograph manuscript volumes, including 211 diaries with daily entries, 1905 January 1-1962 August 7; three volumes containing lists of theater, concerts, and other events attended by Croom-Johnson, 1901-1960; and three volumes containing a daily log of his residences and travels, 1886-1962. Early volumes are copies made by Croom-Johnson from his original diaries, with additional notes made at the time of copying. Entries concern Croom-Johnson's personal and professional life, travel, political events, the Savile Club, and interests in literature, theater and music. Each volume ends with a list of events attended by Croom-Johnson, noting dates, venues, and performers. Affixed to pages are materials relating to the diary entries, including newspaper clippings concerning legal cases, political events, and sports events; newspaper clippings of theater and music reviews; theater and concert programs; illustrated postcards from his travels; letters to Croom-Johnson; and photographs of him, his family, and friends.
Lawyers -- Great Britain; Music -- Great Britain; Theater -- Great Britain; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 20th Century; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 20th Century; Diaries -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Ephemera (general object genre) -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Photographs -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Lawyers -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Croom-Johnson, Norman; Savile Club; Bell, Clarissa -- Ownership; Savile Club -- Ownership
- Diaries, 1886-1962; 34.41 linear feet (89 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Diaries are arranged chronologically, followed by other volumes.
  - Diary, 1905 January 1-December 31 (Box 1)
  - Diary, 1906 January 1-July 10 (Box 1)
  - Diary, 1906 July 11-December 31 (Box 1)
  - Diary, 1907 January 1-June 30 (Box 2)
  - Diary, 1907 July 1-December 31 (Box 2)
  - Diary, 1908 January 1-May 31 (Box 2)
  - Diary, 1908 August 13-26 (Box 3)
  - Diary, 1908 June 1- August 12, August 27-December 31 (Box 3)
  - Diary, 1909 January 1-July 30 (Box 3)
  - Diary, 1909 July 31-December 31 (Box 4)
  - Diary, 1910 January 1-March 22 (Box 4)
  - Diary, 1910 March 23-May 31 (Box 4)
  - Diary, 1910 August 7-23 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1910 June 1-August 6, August 23-December 31 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1911 January 1-April 11 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1911 April 12-19 (Box 6)
  - Diary, 1911 April 20-August 25 (Box 6)
  - Diary, 1911 August 26-December 31 (Box 6)
  - Diary, 1912 January 1-June 30 (Box 7)
  - Diary, 1912 July 1-December 31 (Box 7)
  - Diary, 1913 January 1-May 31 (Box 7)
  - Diary, 1913 June 1-September 15 (Box 8)
  - Diary, 1913 September 16-December 31 (Box 8)
  - Diary, 1914 January 1-June 30 (Box 8)
  - Diary, 1914 July 1-December 31 (Box 9)
  - Diary, 1915 January 1-December 31 (Box 9)
  - Diary, 1916 January 1-December 31 (Box 9)
  - Diary, 1917 January 1-December 31 (Box 10)
  - Diary, 1918 January 1-December 31 (Box 10)
  - Accompanying material, 1918 January 1-December 31 (Box 10)
  - Diary, 1919 January 1-December 31 (Box 11)
  - Diary, 1920 January 1-December 31 (Box 12)
  - Diary, 1921 January 1-December 31 (Box 12)
  - Diary, 1922 January 1-August 17, September 18-December 31 (Box 13)
  - Diary. Holiday tour to Switzerland and the Dolomites, 1922 August 18-September 17 (Box 13)
  - Diary, 1923 January 1-August 21, September 17-December 31 (Box 14)
  - Diary. Holiday tour in the Dolomites, 1923 August 18-September 17 (Box 15)
  - Diary, 1924 January 1-August 9 (Box 15)
  - Diary, 1924 August 10-December 31 (Box 15)
  - Diary, 1925 January 1- June 30 (Box 16)
  - Diary, 1925 July 1-December 31 (Box 16)
  - Diary, 1926 January 1-April 30 (Box 17)
  - Diary, 1926 May 1-August 21, September 23-December 31 (Box 17)
  - Diary. Holiday at Saint-Jean-de-Luz, 1926 August 22-September 22 (Box 17)
  - Diary, 1927 January 1-May 31 (Box 18)
  - Diary. Mediterranean Cruise on R.M.S. Oronsay, 1927 September 9-October 1 (Box 18)
  - Diary, 1927 June 1-September 8, October 2-December 31 (Box 19)
  - Diary, 1928 January 1-August 23 (Box 19)
  - Diary, 1928 August 24-December 31 (Box 20)
  - Diary, 1929 January 1-August 31 (Box 21)
  - Diary, 1929 September 1-December 31 (Box 21)
  - Diary, 1931 January 1-August 5 (Box 21)
  - Diary, 1931 August 6-December 31 (Box 22)
  - Diary, 1932 January 1-July 31 (Box 22)
  - Diary, 1932 August 1-December 31 (Box 22)
  - Diary, 1933 January 1-December 31 (Box 23)
  - Diary, 1934 January 1-July 31 (Box 23)
  - Diary, 1934 August 1-December 31 (Box 24)
  - Diary, 1935 January 1-July 31 (Box 25)
  - Diary, 1935 August 1-December 31 (Box 25)
  - Diary, 1936 January 1-June 30 (Box 25)
  - Diary, 1936 July 1-December 31 (Box 26)
  - Diary, 1937 January 1-June 30 (Box 26)
  - Diary, 1937 July 1-December 31 (Box 26)
  - Diary, 1938 January 1-May 31 (Box 27)
  - Diary. Holiday journal, 1938 August 29-September 25 (Box 27)
  - Diary, 1938 June 1-December 31 (Box 28)
  - Diary, 1939 January 1-July 2 (Box 28)
  - Diary, 1939 July 3-December 31 (Box 29)
  - Diary, 1940 January 1-May 30 (Box 29)
  - Diary, 1940 May 31-September 26 (Box 30)
  - Diary, 1940 September 27-December 31 (Box 30)
  - Diary, 1941 January 1-June 30 (Box 30)
  - Diary, 1941 July 1-December 31 (Box 31)
  - Diary, 1942 January 1-June 30 (Box 31)
  - Diary, 1942 July 1-September 6 (Box 32)
  - Diary, 1942 September 7-December 31 (Box 32)
  - Diary, 1943 January 1-April 29 (Box 32)
  - Diary, 1943 April 30-August 27 (Box 33)
  - Diary, 1943 August 28-December 31 (Box 33)
  - Diary, 1944 January 1-May 31 (Box 34)
  - Diary, 1944 June 1-August 31 (Box 34)
  - Accompanying material, 1944 June 1-August 31 (Box 34)
  - Diary, 1944 September 1-December 31 (Box 34)
  - Diary, 1945 January 1-May 31 (Box 35)
  - Diary, 1945 June 1-August 31 (Box 35)
  - Diary, 1945 September 1-December 31 (Box 35)
  - Diary, 1946 January 1-April 30 (Box 36)
  - Diary, 1946 May 1-June 27, July 18-August 30 (Box 36)
  - Diary. Holiday journal: Denmark and Sweden, 1946 June 28-July 6 (Box 37)
  - Diary. Holiday journal: Denmark and Sweden, 1946 July 7-17 (Box 37)
  - Diary, 1946 August 31-December 31 (Box 38)
  - Diary, 1947 January 1-February 4, February 17-April 30 (Box 38)
  - Diary. Switzerland, 1947 February 5-16 (Box 39)
  - Diary, 1947 May 1-August 26 (Box 40)
  - Diary. Holiday journal: Holland and Belgium, 1947 August 27-31 (Box 40)
  - Diary. Holiday journal: Holland and Belgium, 1947 September 1-8 (Box 40)
  - Diary. Holiday journal: Holland and Belgium, 1947 September 9-16 (Box 41)
  - Diary, 1947 September 17-December 31 (Box 41)
  - Diary, 1948 January 1-April 30 (Box 41)
  - Diary, 1948 May 1-September 1 (Box 42)
  - Diary. France, 1948 September 2-12 (Box 42)
  - Diary. France, 1948 September 13-20 (Box 43)
  - Diary, 1948 September 21-December 31 (Box 43)
  - Diary, 1949 January 1-April 25 (Box 43)
  - Diary. Holland, 1949 April 26-May 1 (Box 44)
  - Diary, 1949 May 2-July 4, July 22-August 31 (Box 44)
  - Diary. France, 1949 July 5-12 (Box 44)
  - Diary. France, 1949 July 18-21 (Box 45)
  - Diary, 1949 September 1-October 6, October 18-December 31 (Box 46)
  - Diary. Ireland, 1949 October 7-17 (Box 46)
  - Diary, 1950 January 1-March 28, April 14-30 (Box 46)
  - Diary. Italy (Milan), 1950 March 29-April 3 (Box 47)
  - Diary. Italy (Florence and Siena), 1950 April 4-7 (Box 47)
  - Diary. Italy, 1950 April 8-13 (Box 47)
  - Diary, 1950 May 1-September 2 (Box 48)
  - Diary. Austria, 1950 September 3-13 (Box 48)
  - Diary. Austria, 1950 September 14-23 (Box 49)
  - Diary, 1950 September 24-December 31 (Box 50)
  - Diary, 1951 January 1-March 31 (Box 50)
  - Diary, 1951 April 1-May 15, June 1-August 20 (Box 51)
  - Diary. France, 1951 May 16-23 (Box 51)
  - Diary. France, 1951 May 24-31 (Box 52)
  - Diary, 1951 August 21-September 26, October 11-November 2 (Box 53)
  - Diary. Paris, 1951 September 27-October 3 (Box 53)
  - Diary. Paris, 1951 October 4-10 (Box 53)
  - Diary, 1951 November 3-December 31 (Box 54)
  - Diary, 1952 January 1-March 31 (Box 54)
  - Diary, 1952 April 1-May 9, June 4-August 10 (Box 54)
  - Diary. Italy, 1952 May 10-27 (Box 55)
  - Diary. Italy, 1952 May 28-June 3 (Box 55)
  - Diary, 1952 August 11-20, September 12-November 1 (Box 55)
  - Diary. Scotland, 1952 August 30-September 5 (Box 56)
  - Diary. Scotland, 1952 September 6-11 (Box 56)
  - Diary, 1952 November 2-December 31 (Box 56)
  - Diary, 1953 January 1-February 28 (Box 57)
  - Diary, 1953 March 1-April 30 (Box 57)
  - Diary, 1953 May 1-June 30 (Box 57)
  - Diary, 1953 July 1-September 11 (Box 58)
  - Diary. Italy, 1953 September 12-19 (Box 58)
  - Diary. Italy, 1953 September 20-24 (Box 58)
  - Diary. Italy, 1953 September 25-28 (Box 59)
  - Diary, 1953 September 29-December 31 (Box 59)
  - Diary, 1954 January 1-February 28 (Box 59)
  - Diary, 1954 March 1-May 31 (Box 60)
  - Diary, 1954 June 1-September 4 (Box 60)
  - Diary. Italy, 1954 September 5-14 (Box 60)
  - Diary. Italy, 1954 September 15-21 (Box 61)
  - Diary. Italy, 1954 September 22-29 (Box 61)
  - Diary. Italy, 1954 September 30-October 4 (Box 61)
  - Diary, 1954 October 5-December 31 (Box 62)
  - Diary, 1955 January 1-April 3 (Box 62)
  - Diary, 1955 April 4-May 15 (Box 62)
  - Diary, 1955 May 16-June 26, July 15-September 1 (Box 63)
  - Diary, 1955 June 27-July 4 (Box 63)
  - Diary, 1955 July 4-9 (Box 63)
  - Diary, 1955 July 10-14 (Box 64)
  - Diary, 1955 September 2-24, October 2-December 31 (Box 64)
  - Diary. Italy, 1955 September 25-October 10 (Box 64)
  - Diary, 1956 January 1-March 31 (Box 65)
  - Diary, 1956 April 1-May 31 (Box 65)
  - Diary, 1956 June 1-August 2, August 19-31 (Box 66)
  - Diary. Yugoslavia, 1956 August 3-10 (Box 66)
  - Diary. Yugoslavia, 1956 August 11-18 (Box 66)
  - Diary. Spain, 1956 September 29-October 4 (Box 67)
  - Diary. Spain, 1956 October 5-9 (Box 67)
  - Diary. Spain, 1956 October 10-15 (Box 67)
  - Diary, 1956 September 1-28, October 16-December 31 (Box 68)
  - Diary, 1957 January 1-March 31 (Box 68)
  - Diary, 1957 April 1-May 12 (Box 68)
  - Diary. Normandy and Brittany, 1957 May 13-22 (Box 69)
  - Diary. Normandy and Brittany, 1957 May 23-June 5 (Box 69)
  - Diary, 1957 June 6-August 30 (Box 69)
  - Diary. Holiday in Italy, 1957 September 13-19 (Box 70)
  - Diary. Holiday in Italy, 1957 September 20-25 (Box 71)
  - Diary. Holiday in Italy, 1957 September 26-30 (Box 71)
  - Diary, 1957 August 31-September 12, October 1- December 31 (Box 72)
  - Diary, 1958 January 1-March 31 (Box 73)
  - Diary, 1958 April 1-May 31 (Box 73)
  - Diary, 1958 June 1-August 15 (Box 74)
  - Diary. S.S. Hermes, Hellenic Cruise, 1958 August 26-31 (Box 75)
  - Diary. S.S. Hermes, Hellenic Cruise, 1958 September 1-7 (Box 75)
  - Diary. S.S. Hermes, Hellenic Cruise, 1958 September 8-13 (Box 75)
  - Diary, 1958 August 16-25, September 14-December 31 (Box 76)
  - Diary, 1959 January 1-March 26 (Box 76)
  - Diary. Belgium, 1959 March 27-31 (Box 76)
  - Diary, 1959 April 1-May 31 (Box 77)
  - Diary, 1959 June 1-July 31 (Box 77)
  - Diary, 1959 August 1-October 5, December 11-31 (Box 77)
  - Diary. India, 1959 October 6-20 (Box 78)
  - Diary. India, 1959 October 21-November 10 (Box 78)
  - Diary. India, 1959 November 11-December 4 (Box 79)
  - Diary. India, 1959 December 5-10 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1960 January 1-April 4 (Box 80)
  - Diary. Greece, 1960 April 5-9 (Box 80)
  - Diary. Greece, 1960 April 10-14 (Box 81)
  - Diary. Greece, 1960 April 15-19 (Box 81)
  - Diary. Greece, 1960 April 20-23 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1960 April 24-July 31 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 1960 August 1-November 4, November 27-December 31 (Box 82)
  - Diary. Tenerife and Spain, 1960 November 5-14 (Box 82)
  - Diary. Tenerife and Spain, 1960 November 15-26 (Box 83)
  - Diary, 1961 January 1-March 27 (Box 83)
  - Diary. Spain, 1961 March 28-April 5 (Box 83)
  - Diary. Spain, 1961 April 6-8 (Box 84)
  - Diary. Spain, 1961 April 9-17 (Box 84)
  - Diary, 1961 April 18-July 27 (Box 84)
  - Diary, 1961 July 28-September 7, September 25-December 31 (Box 85)
  - Diary. Bavaria and Austria, 1961 September 8-13 (Box 85)
  - Diary. Bavaria and Austria, 1961 September 14-18 (Box 86)
  - Diary. Bavaria and Austria, 1961 September 19-24 (Box 86)
  - Diary, 1962 January 1-April 17 (Box 87)
  - Diary, 1962 April 18-August 7 (Box 87)
  - Accompanying material, 1962 April 18-August 7 (Box 87)
  - "Record of Plays, Operas, Ballets, Concerts, Films, etc., Seen", 1901-1923 (Box 88)
  - "Record of Plays, Operas, Ballets, Concerts, Films, etc., Seen", 1924-1946 (Box 88)
  - "Record of Plays, Operas, Ballets, Concerts, Films, etc., Seen", 1947-1960 (Box 88)
  - "Record of Places Lived in or Visited", 1886-1937 (Box 88)
  - "Places Visited", 1938-1946 (Box 89)
  - Log of residences and travels, 1905 January- 1962 September 12 (Box 89)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 89)